ncbex.org 2019-07-08

# NCBE Privacy Policy - NCBE

Date Updated: April 16, 2019

The National Conference of Bar Examiners (“NCBE”) is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes our practices and procedures as they relate to information we collect through our website [www.ncbex.org](http://www.ncbex.org/ "NCBE web site Home page") (the “Site”), however accessed, and information collected when, for example, you provide information to NCBE over the phone or via email, or you participate in NCBE’s examinations (MPRE, MBE, MEE, MPT, or UBE) or other services.

Note that NCBE’s other websites are subject to their own privacy policies at [thebarexaminer.org](https://thebarexaminer.org/privacy-policy/) and [testingtaskforce.org](https://www.testingtaskforce.org/privacy-policy/). And, information you supply when requesting accommodations for the MPRE is subject to the [NCBE Privacy Policy for Applicants Requesting ADA Accommodations for the MPRE](http://www.ncbex.org/exams/mpre/ada-accommodations/).

## Information We Collect

The information we collect varies, depending on the way you use our Site, products, or services. We collect and/or receive information in the ways described below.

### Personal Information

You are not required to provide any personal information to browse or access the public area of the Site. However, to access or use certain NCBE services, including through the Site and when you register for and take an NCBE examination, you may be required to provide personal information. “Personal information” is information that is unique to you, and we may collect the following types of personal information from you:

  * name, including any formerly used names
  * email address
  * telephone number
  * date of birth
  * Social Security or national identification number
  * credit card or debit card number
  * information regarding your legal education, background, credentials, and related matters

Personal information does not include anonymized, aggregate, or statistical information.

### How to Access or Correct Your Personal Information

Access to some of your personal information is available through your [NCBE Account](http://accounts.ncbex.org/php/ncbe_number/). You may log in to your account to edit your account profile or to change your password or email address. Please note that we may require additional information to authenticate your identity. For additional guidance on NCBE Accounts, please review the NCBE Account and NCBE Number section in the [Website Terms of Use](http://www.ncbex.org/website-terms-and-conditions-of-use/).

Note that Certain NCBE services may have specific processes for correcting or updating personal information, such as information submitted in a character and fitness application or associated with a test registration or a score service. Refer to the specific instructions for those services. For additional guidance you can use the [Contact Us](http://www.ncbex.org/contact/) form.

### Automatically Collected Information

Our Site automatically collects certain information about your use of our Site that does not personally identify you. This information includes the following:

  * **Information about your Site activity.  **When you browse our Site, we collect IP address (static or dynamic), browser type and language, operating system, domain server, referring and exit pages and URLs, date and time of visit, length of session, the pages you visited while on the Site, and similar data.
  * **Information about your device.**  When you interact with our Site, we collect information about your device including type of computer or device, operating system and version (e.g., iOS, Android, Windows), carrier and country location, and similar data. Additional information collected from your device may include any of the following: Universally Unique ID (UUID), Advertising Identifier (IDFA), MAC address, hardware and processor information (e.g., storage, chip speed), and network type (e.g., WiFi, 3G, 4G, LTE).

### How We Use Cookies and Tracking Technologies

NCBE and our service partners may use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to receive and store certain information whenever you interact with the Site. Cookies are small data files that are stored or accessed on one's browser each time one visits a website. Cookies may store unique identifiers, user preferences, and other information. Cookies are used by NCBE to keep track of your login information while you are logged in to the Site. We use persistent and non-persistent cookies to make it easier for you to navigate the Site. If you reject cookies, you may still use the Site, but your ability to use some areas of the Site may be limited.

### Use of Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to track interaction with specific features of the Site. You can opt out of Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

### Information We Receive from Third Parties

NCBE may receive information about you from other sources. For example, we regularly receive information from bar admission authorities, third parties contacted as part of a character and fitness investigation, and organizations under contractual agreements to perform services with or on behalf of NCBE, such as testing-administration agencies.

## How We Use the Information We Collect

We use your information to provide, analyze, administer, enhance, and personalize our Site and the products, and services we provide to you. We also use your information to communicate with you and to conduct our business. Generally, NCBE uses your information to carry out its mission to serve the bar admissions community, and more specifically, uses it to

  * provide services and products requested by you, such as testing services, score services, and character and fitness services;
  * provide testing, character and fitness, and other services to bar admission agencies and attorney regulatory authorities;
  * register you for a test, product, or service;
  * complete the NCBE Character and Fitness Application;
  * ensure that our examinations are fair;
  * maintain a permanent record of examinee performance;
  * maintain statistical data and conduct research related to bar admissions, bar examinations, and the legal industry;
  * create or modify an NCBE Account;
  * respond to an inquiry or message you send us through the [Contact Us](http://www.ncbex.org/contact/) form;
  * provide you with updates, reminders, or other information about products and services that you have ordered or that may interest you;
  * analyze and improve our Site or products and/or services;
  * personalize your Site experience;
  * protect you and NCBE from fraudulent transactions, and investigate inappropriate or unauthorized use of NCBE services, products, accounts, or intellectual property or other assets;
  * comply with applicable laws, regulations, or contractual requirements, or respond to subpoenas or government requests; and
  * fulfill any other purpose you request or consent to.

## How We Share and Disclose Your Information

NCBE shares and discloses your information for various purposes in order to provide you the Site, products, and/or services and to conduct our business, including as follows:

  * to service providers (including testing-administration agencies, consultants, payment processors, data hosting and storage providers, and data analytics service providers);
  * to bar admissions authorities that use and/or administer our examinations;
  * for purposes of character and fitness investigations, to bar admission and attorney regulatory authorities and third parties we contact during the investigation;
  * when NCBE reasonably believes it is needed to (i) respond to information requests by law enforcement or other governmental authorities; (ii) comply with any law, regulation, subpoena or other legal process, or court order; (iii) investigate and help prevent security threats, fraud, malicious activity, or inappropriate, unauthorized, or illegal activity involving our examinations, services, or networks; or (iv) enforce or protect our rights and property, including intellectual property;
  * in the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, sale of assets, dissolution, or similar event, as part of the transferred assets; or
  * in accordance with any consent to use or share your information that you provide us.

We may also share anonymized and aggregate data that does not identify you personally, such as for research and analytics purposes.

## Data Retention

Except as set forth in this section regarding your online NCBE Character and Fitness Application, NCBE will retain your personal information for as long as we deem appropriate and necessary in accordance with our legitimate interests and to comply with any applicable laws, regulations, and/or contractual requirements.

We follow the following policies in determining when an online NCBE Character and Fitness Application may be deleted from our website server (and no longer available for you to view or transfer):

  * An unused application may be deleted after 90 days.
  * An application that is never received by NCBE may be deleted after one year of nonuse.
  * An application that is processed by NCBE will remain on our website server for five years from the date we receive the application. As long as your application remains online, you can transfer the data in the application to a new application for a supplemental report to the same jurisdiction or a new report to another jurisdiction (with certain exceptions).
  * An application to North Carolina by Exam will remain on our server for one year from the date the application is received by their admissions office.

If you wish to delete your online NCBE Character and Fitness Application from our website server, please [Contact Us](http://www.ncbex.org/contact/) to determine whether you are eligible to have it removed.

## Security

NCBE has physical, technical, and administrative safeguards in place to protect your personal information. Despite our security measures, no data transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure. As a result, we cannot and do not warrant the security of your personal information.

Messages that you send to us by email, including by use of the [Contact Us form](http://www.ncbex.org/contact/) on the Site, may not be secure, and use of email is not recommended for sending us confidential or sensitive information.

## Links to Third-Party Websites

For your convenience, we may provide links to other websites and web pages that we do not control. NCBE does not endorse and is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any such linked websites. If you submit information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. For information about how other organizations, including testing-administration agencies, may collect and use your personal information, you should review their respective privacy policies when applicable to you.

## Children’s Privacy

This Site is not directed to children under 13 years old. Accordingly, we do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 13 years of age, and persons under 13 years of age should not submit any personal information to NCBE.

## United States Privacy Laws

NCBE is located in the United States. By providing your information, you consent to the processing of your information in the United States.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

NCBE reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time, so you should review it periodically. If we change our policy, the changes will be posted to this Privacy Policy on the Site and the date of the update will be reflected in the Date Updated above. At our discretion, we may also provide notice in NCBE Accounts and on other pages of the Site as we deem appropriate.

## Contact Us

You can submit questions regarding this Privacy Policy by using the [Contact Us form](https://thebarexaminer.org/contact-us/) on the Site.

NCBE can also be contacted at

National Conference of Bar Examiners  
ATTN: NCBE Privacy Policy  
302 South Bedford Street  
Madison, WI 53703-3622

Phone: 608-280-8550  
Fax: 608-280-8552  
TDD: 608-661-1275
